凯特∶你的意思是说我错了.
Kate: So, you're saying I'm wrong.
迈克∶不,不,
Mike: No, no, I'm not saying you're wrong,
我的意思不是说你错了,只是说你对于女人全然不知.
I'm just saying that you know absolutely nothing about women.
凯特∶迈克,
Kate: Mike, there's not a woman in the world who's gonna let you kiss
没有女孩会在你叫错她的名字后还让你吻她.
her after you got her name wrong.
迈克∶卡拉,卡伦,它们的发音都差不多.
Mike: Kara...Karen, I mean, they're so close.
凯特∶她的名字是琼.
Kate: Her name was Joan.
迈克∶当我需要你的时候你在哪里?
Mike: Where were you when I needed you?
凯特:我跟戴维在一起呢,唯一一个比你还不懂女人的.
Kate: I was with David, the only man who knows less about women than you do.
戴维∶好呀.
David: Hiya.
凯特:你去哪儿了?你应该跟我一起吃午饭的.
Kate: Where have you been?You were supposed to meet me here for lunch.
戴维∶宝贝,多多体谅我一下.作为这部戏的编导,
David: Cut me some slack here babe; as director of this play we're doing,
我要负责灯光,道具,还有服装...
I gotta get lights, I gotta get props, I gotta get costumes...
凯特∶但是我是一个人吃饭的.
Kate: But I ate alone.
戴维∶最后压轴戏,必须要十全十美.
David: But for one it has got to be perfect.
你知道索恩教授是多么的严格.
You know what a royal pain in the rrump Professor Thorn is.
杰森∶呃...戴维
Mike: Err...David.
戴维∶让我与你分享一件拉尔夫理查德森的轶事...
David: Let me share with you an anecdote from Rralph Rrichardson...
Professor Thorn: Mr.Home, I roll my R's far more Rrregally than that
迈克∶啊唷!教授,你的口水喷到我了.
Mike: Ow, Professor, you're spitting on me.
索恩教授∶我知道.编导最主要的作用就是观察力,
Professor Thorn: I know.
鲍博,看好它.
A principal role of the Director is observation, so watch it, Bob.
戴维∶哇,兴许我应该道歉.
David: Wow, maybe I should apologise.
凯特∶哦坐下吧,吃完你的三明治,我已经习惯了...手指.
Kate: Oh just sit down, eat your sandwich, I'm used to it...Figures.
迈克∶好了,戴维非常喜爱你.
Mike: Ah, come on, David is crazy about you.
凯特∶是的,那你对男人了解多少?
Kate: Yeah, what do you know about guys?
迈克∶我已经做了15年的男人了.
Mike: Hey, I've been one for the last fifteen years.
凯特∶但是已经19岁了呀.
Kate: But you're nineteen.
迈克∶有趣的故事.
Mike: Interesting story.
本∶爸爸,你是故意让我赢的还是你变老和缓慢了?
Ben: So Dad, did you just let me win, or are you getting old and slow?
杰森∶我故意让你赢的.
Jason: I let you win.
迈克∶嘿爸爸,嘿本.哦!爸爸,这是戴维和凯特,你记得的.
Mike: Hey Dad, hey Ben.Oh, Dad, this is David and you remember Kate.
杰森∶记得.
Jason: Yeah.
迈克∶我们吃完晚餐后,要彩排,可以吗?
Mike: We're gonna be rehearsing after dinner, OK?
杰森:当然可以.
Jason: Yeah, fine.
戴维和凯特∶你好.
David and Kate: Hi there.
本∶我叫本.
Ben: I'm...Ben.
迈克∶她好像很在意你.
Mike: Like she cares.
杰森∶怎么样,还有再来一次吗?
Jason: Alright.Ready to go again?
本∶当然.
Ben: Err...yeah sure.
杰森∶好吧,分数是多少?凯特在像你挥手吗?好!!
Jason: Alright, what's the scores?Is that Kate waving to you?Yes!!
(迈克,戴维和凯特正在彩排--迈克和凯特在表演.)
(Mike, David and Kate rehearsing- Mike and Kate are acting.)
戴维∶火车笛声响起.
David: The train whistle blows.
迈克∶该是做出一个选择的时候了,
Mike: It's time to make a choice,
你是要继续留在城市里,为别人而活,
you can stay here in this town living other people's dreams,
还是要跟我一起离开?
or you can take a chance with me?
凯特∶杰夫,我不能马上就决定我的一生.
Kate: Jeff, I can't decide my whole life in a moment.
迈克∶我们只有一会儿的时间.让我们就此吻别吧,杰西卡.
Mike: Well a moment is all we got.Then kiss me goodbye, Jessica.
戴维∶看,看,
David: Ah!Look, look, look, look!
看,看!
The play's just going great until this kiss here at the end.
这部戏到最后这个吻才算是进入了高潮.迈克,
Mike, you're not kissing her goodbye, you're kissing her hello.
你不是要和她吻别,你是在和她打招呼.
I mean, after this moment,
我是说,
we're supposed to believe she falls in love with you.
等吻过后,我们应该相信她就爱上了你.
I mean, the way you kissed her,
但是你吻她的方式,让人感觉你像是一个拥有很多猫的男人.
I think you're the kind of guy who owns a lot of cats.
好了,从刚才开始吧.
OK, from where we were.
迈克∶我们现在只有一会的时间了.让我们吻别吧,杰西卡.
Mike: A moment's all we got.Then kiss me goodbye, Jessica.
戴维∶唷,迈克,你....你...你是喜欢女孩子的,对吧?
David: Yo, Mike, you...err...you err...like girls, right?
迈克∶当然,我当然是喜欢女孩子的!
Mike: Yes man, of course I like girls!
戴维∶那这里到底是什么问题呢?
David: OK, then what the heck's the problem here?
迈克∶什么问题都没有...不,她是你的女朋友.
Mike: Nothing...no..Well she's your girlfriend.
戴维∶不,她不是.
David: No she's not.
凯特∶再说一次.
Kate: Pardon me.
戴维∶凯特,抛开我不说.
David: OK Kate, bare with me here.
她是一个女演员,你是一个演员;接吻在演员之间根本就不能代表什么.
She's an actress, you're an actor; kisses mean nothing between actors.
迈克∶嘿!
Mike: Hey!
凯特∶好吧,你们2个男人先搞清楚,我要坐会儿.
Kate: Look, while you guys make out, I'm gonna sit down.
戴维∶凯特,不要,好了!再来一次,同样的!
David: Kate, please, OK!Take it again, same page.
凯特∶戴维,我们已经排练了5个小时了,我累死了.
Kate: David, we've been rehearsing for five hours, I'm tired.
戴维∶嘿,这也是你的成绩呢.
David: Hey, it's your grade too.
凯特∶别教育我,我知道是我的成绩.
Kate: Don't lecture me, I know it's my grade.
戴维∶为什么我每次要跟你说点什么的时候,你都会认为我是在教育你呢?
David: Yeah, why is it whenever I've got to make a point with you, you think I'm giving you a lecture?
迈克∶好了,好了,都冷静一下!我会吻你的女朋友,行吗?
Mike: Look, look, look, just calm down!I'll kiss your girlfriend, alright?
戴维∶你为什么就不能学学迈克呢?
David: There, now why can't you be more like Mike?
凯特∶你为什么就不能学学迈克呢?
Kate: Why can't you be more like Mike?
迈克:我同意,
Mike: OK, so we're agreed, I'm a great guy.
他是个好人.
Now can we just call it a night?
戴维∶不行,
David: No, no, we're rapped after we get this kiss right.
不行.我们一定要拍好那个吻才能收工.
Now listen to me, Jessica is...
听我解释,
is the one hope for bringing meaning to your aimless life.
杰西卡是..是给你毫无目标的人生带来意义的人.
All the passion you once held for the open road, you now feel for her.
你对整个世界所有的感情都倾注在了她的身上.
And Jeff is your chance, your one possibility,
而杰夫是你逃脱不幸生活的机会和可能.明白吗?
to escape the life that's trapped you; the life you've outgrown.OK?OK.
火车笛声响起.
Train whistle blows.
迈克∶该是做出一个选择的时候了,你是要继续留在城市里,
Mike: It's time to make a choice, you can stay here in this town,
为别人而活呢,还是要跟我一起离开?
living other people's dreams, or you can take a chance with me.
凯特∶杰夫,我不能马上就决定我的一生.
Kate: Jeff, I can't decide my whole life in one moment.
迈克∶我们现在只有一会的时间了.让我们吻别吧,杰西卡.
Mike: Well a moments all we got.Then kiss me goodbye, Jessica.
戴维∶喔喔!!
David: Woo woo!!
(迈克的梦)
(Mike's dream)
迈克∶我们现在只有一点点的时间了.让我们吻别吧,杰西卡.等等,等等,你能不能把灯光向后移点.谢谢.我要宣布一件事情,我们刚才不是在演戏,我想告诉大家的是,我想告诉全世界的是,我爱凯特麦克旦尼尔.你们从刚才的吻中也能感觉到,她也是爱我的.
Mike: Well a moment's all we got.Then kiss me goodbye, Jessica.Wait, wait, could you please turn the lights back up!Thank you.I've got kind of an announcement to make; see we weren't acting just now, and I want you all to know, heck, I want the whole world to know, that I love Kate McDonnell.And I think as you can tell from that last kiss, she feels the same way about me.
凯特∶迈克!迈克,我们只是演戏.
Kate: Mike!Mike, we're just acting.
迈克∶什么?
Mike: What?
凯特∶迈克!迈克,我们只是在演戏.
Kate: Mike, we're just doing a play.
迈克∶你是说,你不爱我?
Mike: You mean, you're not crazy about me?
凯特∶我甚至都不喜欢你.
Kate: I don't even like you.
索恩教授∶我也不喜欢你,我可是个喜欢挑刺的主.
Professor Thorn: I don't like you either and I'm a royal pain in the rump.
迈克∶大家...你们刚才看见的就是演员之间接吻是不代表任何意义的证明.
Mike: Errm...folks...errm...
让我来演示给你们看.
What you have just seen here is proof that a kiss means nothing between
爸爸,你在这里干什么?
actors.Here let me demonstrate.Dad!!What are you doing here?
杰森∶做这样的梦,你肯定是需要有人来帮帮你.
Jason: With a dream like this, you're gonna need help from somebody.
迈克:爸爸!爸爸!我上楼把他叫醒告诉他我要跟他谈谈.
Mike: Dad!Dad!Well I could go upstairs,
wake him up and tell him I need to talk to him,
or I could be more subtle.
What does it take to get a man out of bed?
开萝尔∶你干什么?我正在要睡着了.
Carol: What are you doing, I'm trying to sleep.
迈克∶我正在设法节省能源呢,开萝尔,
Mike: Well, I'm trying to conserve energy, Carol,
在不是高峰时段使用家用电器.
by running our appliances at off-peak hours.
开萝尔∶你为什么不打开烤面包炉,它不是更静音一点吗?
Carol: Well, why don't you put on the toaster, it's quieter?
迈克:开萝尔,你为什么不上楼,转上三圈睡觉?
Mike: Carol, why don't you go upstairs, circle three times and lay down?
开萝尔∶你肯定有事情.
Carol: You're up to something.
迈克∶我没有.
Mike: No I'm not.
开萝尔∶你退学了.
Carol: You dropped out of school.
迈克∶没有.
Mike: No.
开萝尔∶你把车库烧了!
Carol: You burned down the garage!
迈克∶开萝尔
Mike: Carol.
开萝尔∶你打劫了酒吧!
Carol: You held up a liquor store!
迈克∶开萝尔
Mike: Carol!
开萝尔∶开玩笑而已.
Carol: Don't help me, this is fun.
迈克∶开萝尔,
Mike: OK, Carol, I have question;
我有一个问题;如果你对一个男的没有任何感觉的话,
now could you kiss a guy in a way that would make him think that you
你会吻他吻的让他觉得你很爱他吗?
were nuts about him, when you really don't feel anything at all?
开萝尔∶谁告诉你的,是尼克吗?
Carol: Who told you this, was it Nick?
杰森∶哇,是什么声音?
Jason: What's all the noise?
迈克∶哦,是开萝尔,她正在为和她约会的家伙烦呢.
Mike: Well, it was Carol, she's upset about some guy she's dating.
开萝尔∶什么?
Carol: What?
迈克∶嘿开萝尔,如果我是你,我肯定会踹了他,那个男人一点品位也没有.
Mike: Hey Carol, if I were you I'd dump him; the man's got no taste.
杰森∶晚安.
Jason: Good night.
迈克:等等,爸爸.
Mike: Wait a minute, Dad.
你多久跟我谈一次.
I mean how often do I come to you with my problems?
杰森∶每个星期三;8点钟,7中心.
Jason: Every Wednesday, eight o'clock, seven central.
迈克∶恩,开玩笑.
Mike: Fine, fine, make jokes.
但是,是你告诉我说要我来找你和你谈谈的.
You know, it was your idea for me to come and talk to you.
杰森∶是么?好吧,那我留下来.你想跟我一起吃甜点么?
Jason: It was?Right, well, I better stay.Wanna join me in a late night snack?
迈克:好呀,如果你要找找的话,
Mike: Yeah, if you're looking for it,
我已经把菠萝凯特吃完了.
I already finished the pineapple upside down Kate.
杰森∶菠萝凯特!
Jason: Pineapple upside down Kate!
迈克∶蛋糕!我说的不是蛋糕吗?
Mike: Cake!Didn't I say cake?
杰森∶噢不,不;你说的是凯特.
Jason: Oh no, no; you said Kate.
不是那个今天晚上和你一起彩排的那个女孩子吗?
Isn't that the girl you were rehearsing with tonight?
迈克∶哦爸爸,我整晚都在想她.
Mike: Oh Dad, I can't get her out of my mind!
杰森∶哦!我一点也不惊奇.
Jason: Oh, I don't wonder.
迈克∶爸爸,我甚至做梦都梦见她了...还有你.
Mike: Dad, I mean, she's even in my dreams...you were too.
杰森∶当真??
Jason: Really?
迈克∶没错.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森∶不要和你妈妈说.
Jason: Let's not share that with your mother.
迈克:爸爸,我吻了她以后就难以忘记她了.
Mike: Look Dad, ever since I kissed this girl, I just can't forget about her.
杰森∶你吻了她?
Jason: You kissed her!
迈克:是啊,大概有五十次,她男朋友就站在那里给我鼓掌.
Mike: Oh yeah, about fifty times, with her boyfriend right there, cheering me on!
杰森∶哇,这是梦而已!
Jason: Wow, that is some dream!
迈克∶不是的,爸爸,这些不是梦,是真实发生的.
Mike: No, no, no, Dad, that's not a dream, that actually happened.
杰森∶迈克,你怎么了?
Jason: What the heck are you into, Mike?
迈克∶爸爸,爸爸,我想我是爱上这个女孩子了,可是她已经有男朋友了.
Mike: Dad, Dad, I think I really, really care about this girl but she's taken.
杰森∶那只是你梦的一部分.
Jason: That's part of your dream.
迈克∶不是的,爸爸,你也在那里,我还吻你了!
Mike: No Dad, come on, you were there, I kissed you!
杰森∶迈克,你怎么了?
Jason: What are you into, Mike?
迈克∶爸爸,她根本就不想和我有任何的瓜葛.
Mike: Dad look, she wanted absolutely nothing to do with me at all.
杰森∶这是真实的?
Jason: That's real?
迈克∶不是,是在梦里.
Mike: No, that's the dream.
杰森∶我真希望我是按小时来收你的费的.
Jason: I wish I were charging you by the hour.
迈克∶好吧,让我说简单点,
Mike: OK, I'll make it simple for you; for the first time since Julie,
这是我第一次在朱利走后,在接吻之前爱上一个女孩.
I'm friends with a girl before I kiss her.
杰森∶但是她有男朋友.
Jason: But she has a boyfriend.
迈克∶是.为什么是现在?为什么要爱上她?
Mike: Yes.Why now?Why her?
杰森∶迈克,
Jason: Well, maybe part of what you like about Kate,
也许你喜欢她的一部分原因就是因为她有男朋友了.
is the fact that she is taken, Mike.
也许在你和朱利经历了那么多事情后,你根本就不想很快介入到爱情中,
I mean, maybe after everything you went through with Julie,
所以,
you really don't wanna get involved right now,
你就把这种吸引力转嫁到了已经有男朋友的人的身上.
so you 've concocted this attraction to someone who isn't available.
迈克∶不是这样的.你觉得还有什么原因吗?
Mike: Na, that's not it.What else you got?
杰森∶另外一种可能就是你是真的被她吸引了,
Jason: Well the other possibility is,
因此你想对她认真.
you really are attracted to her and you want to get serious about her.
迈克∶对,对,如果是这样的话,我要怎么做呢?
Mike: OK, OK, now what would I do in this case?
杰森∶什么都不要做.迈克,
Jason: Nothing.No Mike no, not as long as she's got a boyfriend.
不要,既然她已经有了男朋友.你要做的事情就是尽可能的疏远她.
Best thing to do is to have as little to do with her as possible.
迈克∶但是爸爸,可能会有一点棘手的,
Mike: But Dad, it's gonna be kind of tough,
明天从中午直到下午4点半,我还要一直吻她.
I mean I'm kissing this girl tomorrow from noon till four thirty.
杰森∶它会是对性格的一种真正考验.
Jason: It's gonna be a real test of character.
迈克∶她的?我已经怕了.
Mike: Hers?I was afraid of that.
戴维∶好了,让我们从火车汽笛开始,就是接吻前.
David: OK, let's take it from the train whistle.Right before the kiss.
迈克∶戴维,你没有发现诚恳的握手也可以释放感情吗?
Mike: Ah...David have you fully explored the passion of a hearty handshake?
开萝尔∶迈克,我知道了,我知道了,我知道你的问题了!
David: Mike, I know, I know, I know what your problem is!
迈克∶你真的知道了?
Mike: You do?
戴维∶是的,我也找到了解决的办法.
David: Yep and I got the solution.
迈克∶什么,解决的办法就是你离开?
Mike: What, the solution is, you're leaving?
戴维∶不是,不是,
David: No, no, no, no, no, see,
不是,不是,
I got a tape of a train whistle in my car;
在我的车里有一盘火车汽笛的带子,这几天我一直在听.
I've been listening to it for days.
凯特∶哦!戴维,我真喜欢你.
Kate: Oh David, how...like you.
戴维∶你们为什么不练习练习接吻呢,看看是怎么回事.
David: Why don't you guys work up for the kiss, see what happens.
迈克∶你不认为我们应该先做点别的表演练习吗?比如说,
Mike: Err...don't you think maybe we should do some acting exercises first?
假装我们是道具.
You know, like pretending we're furniture.
戴维∶我说了练习接吻!
David: I said work up for the kiss!
凯特∶杰夫,火车马上就要来了,我说,杰夫,火车来了.
Kate: Jeff, the train's coming.I said, Jeff, the train's coming.
迈克∶该是做出一个选择的时候了;你是要继续留在城市里;为别人而活,还是跟我一起离开?
Mike: OK, it's time to make a choice;
you can either stay in this town living out other peoples dreams,
or you can take a chance w
凯特∶杰夫,我不能马上就决定我的一生.
Kate: Jeff, I can't decide my whole life in a moment.
迈克∶我们现在只有一会的时间了.让我们吻别吧,
Mike: Well a moment's all we got.Then kiss me goodbye, Jessica.
杰西卡.
Kate, I'm sorry.
凯特∶迈克,我不是在演戏.
Kate: Mike, I wasn't acting just now.
我知道认为你和我会有一样的感觉的想法很疯狂,
I know I'm crazy to think that you could feel the same,
但是,我是真的喜欢你.
but I really like you.
迈克∶你喜欢我!
Mike: You like me!
凯特∶是的.
Kate: Yeah.
迈克∶太好了,等等,你是像我喜欢你一样喜欢我,还是像你喜欢其他人一样,还是你喜欢我像...我也爱你!一直以来你都说我们只是朋友,所以,我从来都没有想到你会喜欢我...
Mike: Yeah.OK, now wait a minute, do you like me like me like you just...like people you just like, or you like me like...I'm nuts about you too!!So, so you mean this whole time that we were just friends I mean it never occurred...
凯特∶我也没想到.
Kate: Me neither.
迈克∶直到...
Mike: Until just...
凯特∶昨天.
Kate: Yesterday.
戴维∶我告诉你们,我们的问题已经解决了.
David: Guys!I'm telling you our problems are over now.
本∶我打成平局了!
Ben: Yes, I tied it up!
杰森∶对,玩是玩,本,已经不早了,你最好去做你的家庭作业.
Jason: Alright, fun is fun, Ben, it's getting late, you better go and do your homework.
本∶哦,爸爸,再来一次吧.下一个定输赢,怎么样?
Ben: Oh, come on, Dad!How about next basket wins?
杰森∶本,什么更重要呀,
Jason: Ben, what's more important, come on, hoops or home-work?
是篮筐还是家庭作业?快去,我们已经打平了.
Now go on, we're gonna call this a tie.He steals, and deals and...
本∶我要去告诉妈妈!
Ben: I'm telling Mom!
杰森∶好呀?去吧,我倒要看看妈妈是相信你还是相信我?
Jason: Oh yeah?Go ahead, who's she gonna believe anyway?
麦琪∶本,电话,劳拉-林打来的!
Maggie: Ben, telephone, it's Laura-Lynn!
本∶你问问她是谁?
Ben: You asked who it was!
麦琪∶是呀,有问题吗?
Maggie: Yeah, is there a problem?
本:是啊,她现在一定以为别的女孩给我打电话了.我死定了.
Ben: Yeah, now she's gonna think that other girls call me too.I'm a dead man.
迈克:听着,已经结束了.妈妈好.
Mike: Hey listen, now that you've finished with the game...oh, hi Mom.
麦琪∶嘿迈克,我最近几天很少看见你,有什么事吗?
Maggie: Hey Mike, I hardly see you these days, what's new?
迈克∶没什么.
Mike: Nothing.
麦琪∶明天晚上的戏排好了吗?
Maggie: You all ready for the play tomorrow night?
迈克∶恩.
Mike: Yep.
麦琪∶哦,你们有话要说?
Maggie: Oh, you guys wanna talk, huh?
迈克∶哦,没有,没有,没有,没有,等你离开我们再说.
Mike: Oh, no, no, no, no, it's OK, we'll wait till you leave.
麦琪∶哦,如果你想问关于女人的建议,就听他的,杰森.
Maggie: Oh, if you're asking for advice about women...listen to him, Jason.
迈克∶爸爸,爸爸,今天发生了最糟糕的事情.
Mike: Dad, Dad, the worst thing happened to me today.
杰森∶为什么,你告诉了她你的感觉?
Jason: Why, did you tell her how you feel?
迈克∶不是,是她告诉了我她的感觉!
Mike: No, she told me how she feels!
杰森∶她有什么感觉?
Jason: How does she feel.
迈克∶非常好!
Mike: Pretty darn good!
杰森∶迈克!
Jason: Mike!
迈克∶不,不,不,爸爸,我也不想这样的事情发生.
Mike: No, no, no, Dad, I mean I didn't want this to happen.
杰森∶别装了,你不想?
Jason: Come on, you didn't?
迈克∶好吧,我当然想.但是,我过去不想它发生.我想只是我太有魅力了.
Mike: Oh, well of course I did.But I didn't want it want it to
happen.I guess I'm just irresistible
杰森∶迈克,你明知道不该这样的.
Jason: Come on Mike, you know better than this.
迈克∶爸爸,难道你认识我存心破坏他们的关系?
Mike: Dad, come on, you think I wanted to mess up their relationship?
杰森:我没有.对不起,
Jason: No, OK, I don't.I'm sorry, I just...
我只是对你有成见.
I have a prejudice against guys like you.
迈克∶你说什么?
Mike: Pardon me?
杰森∶你知道吗,当我最初和你妈妈约会的时候,
Jason: Hey, look, when I was dating your mother at the start,
我们也曾经发生过一两次的矛盾.
we had a snag or two, that happens.So, what do I do?
所以,我就去找我的朋友亚伦倾诉,
I turn to my friend Aaron; this guy's my...
亚伦是我实验室的搭档.
my lab partner, for crying out loud.
在我告诉他所有的事情后,他就开始接近你的妈妈.
Before I know it I tell him the whole story and then he starts,
他约她出去,
he's sniffing around your mother.He's taking her out, he...he...
还收集卡片,以此来打动她...
he starts picking up the tab, like that's gonna imp
迈克∶爸爸,这和我一点关系也没有,我连实验室都没有!
Mike: Dad, this is nothing to do with me, I don't even have lab!
杰森∶问题在于,
Jason: The point is, Mike,
迈克,
that Aaron just being there was getting in the way of me getting back
亚伦的介入差点让我无法再得到你妈妈...
with your mother again.
迈克∶但是爸爸,他们之间的问题也和我没有关系!
Mike: But Dad, I have nothing to do with their problems!
杰森∶你敢肯定?
Jason: Are you sure of that?
迈克∶是的,爸爸,
Mike: Yeah Dad, I mean they were having problems long before I even knew
他们很早以前就有问题了,那时我都还不知道我喜欢她,她也不知道她喜欢我.
that even liked her, before she even knew that she liked me.
杰森∶嘿,只有2个人才知道.
Jason: Hey, only two people could know that for sure.
迈克∶我和凯特.不要再管我了,不要再管我了.
Mike: Me and Kate.Don't help me, don't help me.
索恩教授∶晚上好,
Professor Thorn: Good evening parents and friends of the Alf landen Junior
父母们,
College department of Arts.And Welcome to the Ruth Buzzy theater.
阿尔福蓝登学院艺术系的朋友们,欢迎来到路得步姿剧院.
Tonight we are pleased to present three student one acts;
我们很高兴今晚能给大家表演;我们的第一个节目是试验的,
our first production is an experimental piece, entitled, Mr.
题目是林肯先生来到剧院.
Lincoln goes to the theatre.
杰森∶抱歉我们来迟了.
Jason: Sorry we're late.
索恩教授∶哦,快找座位坐下吧.
Professor Thorn: Oh, find a seat, yes, find a seat.
本∶我不要和这个家伙坐在一起!因为他的老婆会打他.
Ben: I'm not sitting next to this guy!So his wife shot him.
索恩教授∶好,我们现在给时间给大家从刚才的表演中恢复过来,
Professor Thorn: Ah, we'll give you a moment to recover from that as we
因为我们正在为下一个表演布置舞台.
set the stage for our next one act.
麦琪∶那儿有他的名字,迈克尔亚伦西维尔,下一个就是他的节目了.
Maggie: There's his name, Michael Aaron Seaver.His play's next.
杰森∶那是我的儿子.迈克尔亚伦...
Jason: That's my boy.Michael Aaron...
麦琪,为什么你坚持用亚伦做中间名?
Maggie, why did you insist on middle name being Aaron?
麦琪∶哦,我不知道,不记得了.
Maggie: Oh, I don't know, I can't remember.
杰森∶好好想想.
Jason: Well think.
麦琪∶哦!那是我堂兄的名字.
Maggie: Oh, it was after my cousin.
杰森:是的,对.
Jason: Yeah, right.
麦琪∶与那个为我买午餐的有魅力的男孩子无关,
Maggie: It had nothing to do with that charming boy who paid for my lunches,
他现在好像已经是个百万富翁了.
who now, by the way, is a millionaire.
索恩教授∶接下来的节目是一个戏剧疑问,
Professor Thorn: Our next production poses a dramatic question,
如果罗密欧和朱丽叶是滑稽戏会是什么样的呢?
what if Romeo and Juliet were mimes?
开萝尔∶如果林肯看到了这部戏,一定会想自杀的.
Carol: If Lincoln were here to see this play, he'd kill himself.
本∶真棒;真棒!
Ben: That was great, that was great!
开萝尔∶你为什么这样说?
Carol: How can you say that?
本∶我可以看见她的内衣.
Ben: Well I could see right down her dress.
戴维∶我们马上就要出场了,该死的迈克跑哪儿去了?
David: We're on next, where the heck is Mike?
凯特∶我不知道.
Kate: I don't know.
戴维∶哦!也许这些滑稽戏会被要求重演...我在和谁开玩笑?
David: Oh, maybe those mimes will get an encore...who am I kidding?
凯特∶迈克,你去哪里了?
Kate: Mike, where have you been?
迈克∶我在练台词.
Mike: I was running my lines.
凯特∶在哪里,我到处都找过了.
Kate: Where, I've been looking all over for you.
迈克∶凯特,我们可不可以只演戏?
Mike: Ah, look Kate, can we just stick to the play.
凯特∶迈克,你不能一直逃避我.
Kate: Mike, you can't keep avoiding me.
迈克∶我只是不想讨论我们现在不能讨论的事情,行吗?
Mike: It's just that I don't wanna talk about things that we can't talk about right now, OK?
戴维:迈克!好吧,要记得,吻以为着一切.
David: Mike!OK guys, this is it, and remember, that kiss means everything.
杰森∶麦琪,你为什么一直和亚伦保持联系?
Jason: Maggie, why are you keeping in touch with this Aaron guy?
麦琪∶嘘.
Maggie: Sshh.
我们今天最后的一个节目,叫热情.
Professor Thorn: Our final one act of the evening is titled, The Passion,
凯特麦克旦尼尔和迈克尔西维尔主演.
starring Kate McDonnell and Michael Seaver.
麦琪∶喔,借光.
Maggie: Woo!Excuse me.
索恩教授∶导演戴维霍格,
Professor Thorn: And directed by David Hogue,
他和女主角很明显没有任何瓜葛.
who's apparently not related to this lady at all.
杰森∶我有问题要问你,麦琪.
Jason: I asked you a question, Maggie.
麦琪∶杰森,听着,
Maggie: Jason, listen, I wanna watch and see how Mike deals with having
我想要看看迈克会怎样处理在知道凯特喜欢他,
to kiss Kate,
而她男朋友却是编导的情况下,他和凯特的接吻.
knowing how Kate feels and that her boyfriend's the director.
杰森∶你偷听!那你根本就没有和那个家伙联系,对吗?
Jason: You eavesdropped!So you're not really keeping in touch with this guy at all, are you?
麦琪∶没有,如果你还不住嘴的话,我就会了.
Maggie: No.But I could if you don't dummy up.
(戏剧)
(The Play)
迈克∶是做出一个选择的时候了;你要继续留在城市里,为别人而活;还是要跟我一起离开?
Mike: OK, it's time to make a choice; you can stay here in this town
living other people's dreams or you can take a chance with me
凯特∶杰夫,我不能马上就决定我的一生.
Kate: Jeff, I can't decide my whole life in a moment.
迈克∶我们现在只有一会的时间了.让我们吻别吧,杰西卡.(他们接吻)
Mike: Well a moment's all we got.Then kiss me goodbye, Jessica.(They kiss)
杰森:哇.
Jason: Wow
本∶这才能叫家庭作业.
Ben: That's what I call homework.
凯特∶哦!迈克!
Kate: Oh Mike!
迈克∶哦!凯特,我再也不能隐藏我对你的感情了!我希望我可以,
Mike: Oh Kate, I can't hide my feelings for you any more!
但是,我真的不行.也许这样做是错的.
I wish I could, but I can't.Maybe this is wrong.
凯特∶不,不,没有错.
Kate: No, no, it's not wrong.
迈克∶我们向戴维去解释.
Mike: We'll explain this to David.
凯特∶是的,我们要告诉他,我们并不是有意要让它发生的.
Kate: Yeah, we'll just tell him that we didn't plan for it to happen.
迈克∶对,我们甚至都不希望它发生.
Mike: Yeah and that we didn't even want it to happen.
凯特∶他会理解我们的.
Kate: He'll understand.
迈克∶恩,是的,他是一个不错的家伙.
Mike: Oh yeah, he's a great guy.
凯特∶恩,是的,他是一个不错的家伙.
Kate: Oh, yeah, he's a great great guy.
戴维∶好你们2个!你们演的太好了!宝贝,
David: You guys!You guys were great!
我知道最近几个礼拜我的表现差到了极点,但是,
Oh look honey, I know I've been a total jerk for the last few weeks,
我知道我们可以重新来过,凯蒂,我爱你.
but I know we can get things back the way they were, Katie.I love you.
索恩教授:好的,该谢幕了.
戴维∶我们走!
00:21:23,300
Professor Thorn: Alright people, it's time for the bows. David: Let's go!